Mss.530.1.Ar2
American Philosophical Society
- I. Papers
  - Niels Bohr Manuscripts, 1904-1962; 27.0 Reel(s); Bohr, Niels Henrik David, 1885-1962 (Reel Bohr MSS 1-27)
    - Elements within the first period, 1921; 10.0 p.; Bohr, Niels Henrik David, 1885-1962 (Reel Bohr MSS 9, Reel-frame 4)
    - Constitution of atoms, 1921-1922; 27.0 p.; Bohr, Niels Henrik David, 1885-1962 (Reel Bohr MSS 10, Reel-frame 1)
    - Atomic theory and periodic system, 1921-1922; 115.0 p.; Bohr, Niels Henrik David, 1885-1962 (Reel Bohr MSS 10, Reel-frame 2)
    - Bemerkungen über den Atombau [Remarks on the atomic structure], 1922; 20.0 p.; Bohr, Niels Henrik David, 1885-1962 (Reel Bohr MSS 10, Reel-frame 3)
    - Lectures, London and Cambridge, 1922; 9.0 p.; Bohr, Niels Henrik David, 1885-1962 (Reel Bohr MSS 10, Reel-frame 3)
    - Guthrie lecture, 1922; 129.0 p.; Bohr, Niels Henrik David, 1885-1962 (Reel Bohr MSS 10, Reel-frame 4)
    - Die Theorie des Atombaus [The theory of atomic structure], 1922; 119.0 p.; Bohr, Niels Henrik David, 1885-1962 (Reel Bohr MSS 10, Reel-frame 5)
    - Forklaringen af det periodiske system [The explanation of the periodic system], 1922; 16.0 p.; Bohr, Niels Henrik David, 1885-1962 (Reel Bohr MSS 10, Reel-frame 6)
    - Kvanteteoriens anvendelse [Application of the quantum theory], 1922; 5.0 p.; Bohr, Niels Henrik David, 1885-1962 (Reel Bohr MSS 10, Reel-frame 6)
    - Ukomplet manuscript [Incomplete manuscript], 1922; 16.0 p.; Bohr, Niels Henrik David, 1885-1962 (Reel Bohr MSS 10, Reel-frame 6)
    - Veröffentlichte Werke [Published Works], 1922; 1.0 p.; Bohr, Niels Henrik David, 1885-1962 (Reel Bohr MSS 10, Reel-frame 6)
    - Tale ved tildelingen af Nobelprisen [Speech at the award of the Nobel prize], 1922; 2.0 p.; Bohr, Niels Henrik David, 1885-1962 (Reel Bohr MSS 10, Reel-frame 6)
      Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark.
      Rutherford Collection, Cavendish Laboratory, Cambridge, England. Letters to Ernest Rutherford, 1912-1936.
      Royal Society Library, London, England. Letter, 1921.
      Deutsche Staatsbibliothek, Berlin, Germany. Letter to Max Planck, 1923 (Darmstaedter Collection, Fic* 1911).
      Rijksmuseum voor de Geschiedenis der Natuurwetenschappen, Leiden, Netherlands. Approximately 20 letters to Paul Ehrenfest, 1922-1932.
      Library of the Swedish Academy, Stockholm, Sweden. Letters to C. W. Oseen, 11 letters, 1911-1930.
      Universitetsbiblioteket, Uppsala, Sweden. Letter to Manne Siegbahn, 1923 (Waller Collection).
      Pauli Collection, Zurich, Switzerland. Letters to Wolfgang Pauli, 34 letters, 1922-1955.
      Library of Congress, Washington, D.C. Correspondence with Oswald Veblen, 1928-1947.
      Einstein Collection, Princeton, New Jersey. Correspondence with Albert Einstein, 10 letters, 1920-1954.
      American Institute of Physics, New York, New York. Letters to Gordon Fulcher, 3 letters, 1923.
    - Manuscripts, 1923-1945; 6.0 Reel(s); Bohr, Niels Henrik David, 1885-1962 (Reel Bohr MSS 11-16)
    - Manuscripts, 1946-1962; 10.0 Reel(s); Bohr, Niels Henrik David, 1885-1962 (Reel Bohr MSS 17-26)
    - Index, 1904-1962; 1.0 Reel(s); Niels Bohr institutet. (Reel Bohr MSS 27)
      Table of contents to Bohr Manuscript Reels 1-27.
  - Memoirs, recollections of the advent of electron spin, 1959; 3.0 p.; Bohr, Niels Henrik David, 1885-1962; Waerden, B. L. van der, (Bartel Leendert), 1903-1996 (Reel 66, Reel-frame 6)
  - Card Index of Bohr Manuscripts and Papers, 1904-1922; 1.0 Reel(s); Niels Bohr institutet. (Reel Bohr MSS 10a)
  - Catalog of the Bohr Scientific Correspondence, 1962-1963; 1.0 Reel(s); Niels Bohr institutet. (Reel 48)
    This card catalog was prepared at the Bohr Sekretariat by Fru E. Tanggaard and Mag. E. Rüdinger. For many of the pre-1923 letters Rüdinger prepared, and the card bears, a summary of the contents of the letter and English translations of key phrases. All cards which had been annotated at the time of filming appear also on Microfilms BSC 1-8.
  - Parody of "Faust", 1932; 24.0 p.; Niels Bohr institutet. (Reel 66, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1899; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Boltzmann, Ludwig, 1844-1906 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 11)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1940; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Bonhoeffer, Karl Friedrich, 1899-1957 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 11)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1937-1938; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Bonino, Giovanni Battista, 1899-1985 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 11)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1948-1949; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (6 pages); Bopp, Friedrich Arnold, 1909–1987 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 11)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1949; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Bork, Alfred M. (Reel 12, Reel-frame 16)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1925; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Born, Hedwig (Reel 8, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 12 May 1918; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Born, Max, 1882-1970 (Reel BSC 1, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Charles Galton Darwin, 7 April 1927; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Born, Max, 1882-1970 (Reel 36, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Walther Gerlach, 11 May 1921 - 27 December 1929; 16.0 Item(s) 16 letters (29 pages); Born, Max, 1882-1970 (Reel 19, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Edwin C. Kemble, 9 March 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Born, Max, 1882-1970 (Reel 51, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 15 February 1925 - 1951; 11.0 Item(s) 11 letters; Born, Max, 1882-1970 (Reel 8, Reel-frame 2, Reel 9, Reel-frame 5, Reel 11, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Alfred Landé, 21 December 1918 - 15 July 1924; 20.0 Item(s) 20 letters (59 pages); Born, Max, 1882-1970 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Erwin Schrödinger, 6 November 1926 - 1957; 34.0 Item(s) 34 letters (127 pages); Born, Max, 1882-1970 (Reel 41, Reel-frame 7, Reel 37, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 15 June 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Born, Max, 1882-1970 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 11)
  - Letters to J. H. Van Vleck, 24 October 1924 - 25 February 1926; 5.0 Item(s) 5 letters (5 pages); Born, Max, 1882-1970 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Gregor Wentzel, 13 December 1926 - 15 December 1926; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Born, Max, 1882-1970 (Reel 66, Reel-frame 3)
  - Lecture course, "Kinetische Gastheorie," notes taken by Maria Mayer, Göttingen, 1928; 125.0 p.; Born, Max, 1882-1970; Mayer, Maria Goeppert, 1906-1972 (Reel 2)
  - Memoirs, "Professor Max Born's Recollections: Excerpts from Chapters X, XII, and XVI", 11.0 p.; Born, Max, 1882-1970 (Reel 66, Reel-frame 7)
  - Memoirs, "XIX. Quantum Mechanics", n.d.; 18.0 p.; Born, Max, 1882-1970 (Reel 66, Reel-frame 7)
  - Memoirs, "Second Part: Tempestuous Years. 1. The Heroic Age of Theoretical Physics", 20.0 p.; Born, Max, 1882-1970 (Reel 66, Reel-frame 7)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 69 letters, 1923-1961. Letter to F. Simon, 1945. Statement by Born regarding Paul Hertz, February 18, 1935.
    Rutherford Collection, Cavendish Laboratory, Cambridge, England. Letters to Ernest Rutherford, 3 letters, 1931-1936.
    Bedford College Library, University of London, London, England. Letters to William Wilson, 2 letters, 1950-1952.
    Mathematisches Institut, University of Göttingen, Göttingen, Germany. Ausarbeitungen of lecture courses, "Kinetische Theorie der Materie," winter, 1922/1923; "Quantenmechanik," winter, 1928/1929; "Quantentheorie," summer, 1930.
    Rijksmuseum voor de Geschiedenis der Natuurwetenschappen, Leiden, Netherlands. Approximately 20 letters to Paul Ehrenfest with copies of answers, 1927-1932.
    Library of the Swedish Academy, Stockholm, Sweden. Letters to C. W. Oseen, 4 letters, 1915-1936.
    Bibliothek der Eidgenössischen Technischen Hochschule, Zurich, Switzerland. Letters to Hermann Weyl, 3 letters, 1925-1930.
    Pauli Collection, Zurich, Switzerland. Letter to Wolfgang Pauli, 1919.
    Burndy Library, Norwalk, Connecticut. Manuscript in the Weiner Collection.
    Library of Congress, Washington, D.C. Correspondence with Oswald Veblen, 1940.
    University of Maryland, College Park, Maryland. Born's library plus a collection of reprints, some of them annotated.
    Einstein Collection, Princeton, New Jersey. Correspondence with Albert Einstein, approximately 75 items, 1916-1954.
    Duke University Archives, Durham, North Carolina. 20 letters to Fritz London, 1929-1937.
    Other information
    Professor Born has said that he left many papers in Göttingen when he went to England in 1933. These papers have not as yet been located.
  - Letter to Edwin C. Kemble, 1931; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Boston Society for Psychic Research. (Reel 53, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1945; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (7 pages); Böttcher, C. J. F., (Carl Johan Friedrich), 1915-2008 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1949; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Bottema, O., (Oene) (Reel 11, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 5 July 1924 - 8 March 1928; 25.0 Item(s) 25 letters (63 pages); Bourgin, David Gordon, b. 1900 (Reel 51, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1951; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Boutry, G. A., (Georges Albert) (Reel 11, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1949; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (4 pages); Bouwkamp, C. J., (Christoffel Jacob) (Reel 29, Reel-frame 11)
  - Letter to Allen Goodrich Shenstone, 1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Bowen, Ira Sprague, 1898-1973 (Reel 59, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 29 March 1920; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Bragg, William Henry, Sir, 1862-1942 (Reel BSC 1, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 7 February 1911 - 1947; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (12 pages); Bragg, William Henry, Sir, 1862-1942 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 12)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. 3 letters to Niels Bohr, 1938-1939.
    Rutherford Collection, Cavendish Laboratory, Cambridge, England. 2 letters to Ernest Rutherford, 1904-1933.
    Bedford College Library, University of London, London, England. 2 letters to William Wilson, 1923, n.d.
    Royal Society Library, London, England. 15 letters, 1907-1931.
    Deutsche Staatsbibliothek, Berlin, Germany. Material at present held at the Westdeutschen Bibliothek, Marburg/Lahn, Germany. 2 Letters to O. Hahn, 1908; 3 to Dr. Iklé, 1913. (Darmstaedter Collection, F2c 1912).
    Einstein Collection, Princeton, New Jersey. Correspondence with Albert Einstein, 2 letters, 1931.
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1946-1950; 7.0 Item(s) 7 letters (16 pages); Bragg, William Lawrence, Sir, 1890-1971 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letters to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 14 September 1922 - 9 April 1932; 13.0 Item(s) 13 letters (29 pages); Breit, Gregory, 1899-1981 (Reel 60, Reel-frame 1, Reel-frame 7, Reel 65, Reel-frame 1-3, Reel 64, Reel-frame 4-6, Reel-frame 6-7)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 26 September 1924; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Breit, Gregory, 1899-1981 (Reel 8, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Erwin Schrödinger, 17 February 1927; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Breit, Gregory, 1899-1981 (Reel 41, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 2 June 1930; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Breit, Gregory, 1899-1981 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letters to J. H. Van Vleck, 25 January 1926 - 1 April 1929; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Breit, Gregory, 1899-1981 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 3)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 12 letters, 1933-1954.
    Einstein Collection, Princeton, New Jersey. Correspondence with Albert Einstein, 3 letters, 1922-1935.
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1946; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Brickwedde, F. G., (Ferdinand Graft), 1903-1989 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1925; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Briggs, George Henry (Reel 29, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1940; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (5 pages); Brill, Rudolf (Reel 29, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 29 April 1921; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Brillouin, Leon, 1889-1969 (Reel BSC 1, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 1 July 1922 - 21 December 1932; 14.0 Item(s) 14 letters (23 pages); Brillouin, Leon, 1889-1969 (Reel 65, Reel-frame 8, Reel-frame 3, Reel-frame 5, Reel 63, Reel-frame 5-6, Reel-frame 1, Reel 60, Reel-frame 2-3)
  - Letters to Erwin Schrödinger, May 1956 - August 1956; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (4 pages); Brillouin, Leon, 1889-1969 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 28 November 1934 - 31 December 1935; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Brillouin, Leon, 1889-1969 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letter to J. H. Van Vleck, 20 March 1932; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Brillouin, Leon, 1889-1969 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 3)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 17 letters, 1925-1959.
    Library of the Swedish Academy, Stockholm, Sweden. 2 letters to C. W. Oseen, 1937-1938.
    Bibliothek der Eidgenössischen Technischen Hochschule, Zurich, Switzerland. Letter to Hermann Weyl, 1930.
    Einstein Collection, Princeton, New Jersey. Correspondence with Albert Einstein, 3 letters, 1926-1929.
    American Institute of Physics, New York, New York. Autobiographical memoir.
    Duke University Archives, Durham, North Carolina. 3 letters to Fritz London, 1931-1945.
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1936; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Brillouin, Marcel, 1854-1948 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1950; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (12 pages); Brinkelman, C. (Reel 11, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1937-1952; 17.0 Item(s) 17 letters (59 pages); Brinkman, Henri Coenraad (Reel 11, Reel-frame 10, Reel 9, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Edwin C. Kemble, 1936; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Brinsmade, James B., 1884-1936 (Reel 53, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Werner Heisenberg, 16 December 1931; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Broglie, Louis de, 1892-1987 (Reel 45, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Erwin Schrödinger, November 1933; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter; Broglie, Louis de, 1892-1987 (Reel 43, Reel-frame 4)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letter to Constantin Bedreag, 1942. Letters to Niels Bohr, 9 letters, 1934-1952.
    Bedford College Library, University of London, London, England. 3 letters to William Wilson, 1948-1953.
    Einstein Collection, Princeton, New Jersey. Correspondence with Albert Einstein, 12 letters, 1929-1955 (bulk 1951-1955).
  - Notes on Langevin Seminars, 1919-1927; 1.0 Reel(s); Broglie, Louis de, 1892-1987 (Reel 85)
    L. de Broglie, Paris.
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 1913; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Brønsted, J. N., (Johannes Nicolaus), 1879-1947 (Reel BSC 1, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1930; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Bruce, Harold Lawton, 1887-1934 (Reel 51, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1938; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Brück, H. A., (Hermann Alexander), 1905-2001 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 13)
  - Letter to Allen Goodrich Shenstone, 1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Bruin, Take Luite de (Reel 59, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1934; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Bruin, Take Luite de (Reel 29, Reel-frame 13)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1947; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Bruining, H. (Reel 11, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1941-1944; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (15 pages); Bruins, S. M. (Reel 11, Reel-frame 11)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1944; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Bruynzeel Deurenfabriek. (Reel 11, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1899-1902; 10.0 Item(s) 10 letters (46 pages); Bryan, G. H., (George Hartley), 1864-1928 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 13)
  - Letter to Alfred Landé, 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Bucherer, A. H., (Alfred Heinrich), b. 1863 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 15)
  - Letters to Walther Gerlach, 28 January 1922 - 23 February 1922; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Buchwald, Eberhard, 1886-1975 (Reel 19, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Erwin Schrödinger, November 1933; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter; Buchwald, Eberhard, 1886-1975 (Reel 43, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 15 February 1934 - 12 March 1935; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Buchwald, Eberhard, 1886-1975 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 14)
  - Letter to Alfred Landé, 4 May 1924; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Burger, Herman Carel, 1893-1965 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 15)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 9 June 1921; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Burgers, J. M., (Johannes Martinus), 1895-1981 (Reel BSC 1, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to K. Blokhuis, 1940; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Burgers, J. M., (Johannes Martinus), 1895-1981 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letters to Paul Ehrenfest, 1923 - 6 July 1932; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (9 pages); Burgers, J. M., (Johannes Martinus), 1895-1981 (Reel 75, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 4 May 1926 - 19 July 1926; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Burgers, J. M., (Johannes Martinus), 1895-1981 (Reel 60, Reel-frame 7-8)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1940-1943; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (9 pages); Burgers, J. M., (Johannes Martinus), 1895-1981 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letter to Alfred Landé, 7 April 1919; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Burgers, J. M., (Johannes Martinus), 1895-1981 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 15)
  - Letter to Adalbert Rubinowicz, 25 November 1919; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Burgers, J. M., (Johannes Martinus), 1895-1981 (Reel 17, Reel-frame B)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letter to Niels Bohr, 1931.
    Library of the Swedish Academy, Stockholm, Sweden. Letters to C. W. Oseen, 6 letters, 1927-1930.
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1899-1906; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (8 pages); Burkhardt, Heinrich, 1861-1914 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 14)
  - Letters to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 1932; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Burns, Keivin, 1881-1958 (Reel 65, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letter to Allen Goodrich Shenstone, 1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Burns, Keivin, 1881-1958 (Reel 59, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1936-1938; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Burton, E. F., (Eli Franklin), b. 1879 (Reel 9, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1932; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Bush, Vannevar, 1890-1974 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 14)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Cabrera, Blas, 1878-1945 (Reel 30, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1923; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Campo, Angel del (Reel 30, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 1931; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Campbell, E. C. (Reel 65, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Carathéodory, Constantin, 1873-1950 (Reel 31, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1897-1900; 15.0 Item(s) 15 letters (55 pages); Carslaw, H. S., (Horatio Scott), 1870-1954 (Reel 30, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1949; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Carter, Ashley H., 1924-2008 (Reel 12, Reel-frame 16)
  - Letters to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 9 April 1929 - 9 January 1931; 6.0 Item(s) 6 letters (23 pages); Casimir, H. B. G., (Hendrik Brugt Gerhard), 1909-2000 (Reel 64, Reel-frame 5, Reel 63, Reel-frame 7, Reel-frame 3-4, Reel 65, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1941-1946; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Casimir, H. B. G., (Hendrik Brugt Gerhard), 1909-2000 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letter to J. H. Van Vleck, 23 September 1957; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Casimir, H. B. G., (Hendrik Brugt Gerhard), 1909-2000 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 4)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 13 letters, 1929-1948.
    Bibliothek der Eidgenössischen Technischen Hochschule, Zurich, Switzerland. Letter to Hermann Weyl, 1931.
    Pauli Collection, Zurich, Switzerland. Letter to Wolfgang Pauli, undated.
    Duke University Archives, Durham, North Carolina. Letters to Fritz London, 7 letters, 1932-1945.
  - Letter to Allen Goodrich Shenstone, 7 August 1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Catalan, Miguel Angel, 1894-1957 (Reel 59, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 19 April 1923 - 12 April 1939; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (7 pages); Catalan, Miguel Angel, 1894-1957 (Reel 30, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1944; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); D. B. Centen, Uitgevers Maatschappij. (Reel 11, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1951; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Chadwick, James, Sir, 1891-1974 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letters to Christian Møller, 1931; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (5 pages); Champion, F. C., (Frank Clive) (Reel 59, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to Paul Ehrenfest, 1928; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (3 pages); Chapman, Sydney, 1888-1970 (Reel 62, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 1928-1929; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (4 pages); Chapman, Sydney, 1888-1970 (Reel 62, Reel-frame 2, Reel 63, Reel-frame 7, Reel-frame 4, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 1915-1916; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (5 pages); Christiansen, C., (Christian), 1843-1917 (Reel BSC 1, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1937-1948; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letter (10 pages); Christiansen, Jens Anton, 1888-1969 (Reel 9, Reel-frame 6, Reel 11, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1946; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Christlein, Günther (Reel 30, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1946; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Clarendon Laboratory. (Reel 13, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1937-1948; 12.0 Item(s) 12 letters (27 pages); Clay, Jacob, 1882-1955 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 13, Reel 9, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1938-1939; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Clusius, Klaus, 1903-1963 (Reel 30, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1948-1951; 7.0 Item(s) 7 letters (7 pages); Cockcroft, John, Sir, 1897-1967 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 12)
  - Memorandum to Rutherford on "The Probability of Artificial Disintegration by Protons", 1928; 1.0 p.; Cockcroft, John, Sir, 1897-1967 (Reel 66, Reel-frame 2)
    Unpublished materials held elsewhere
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 35 letters, 1930-1961.
    Rutherford Collection, Cavendish Laboratory, Cambridge, England. 2 letters to Ernest Rutherford, 1932. Letter to Walton and Dee, undated.
    Duke University Archives, Durham, North Carolina. 2 letters to Fritz London, 1935.
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1901; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (8 pages); Cohn, Emil, 1854-1944 (Reel 30, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 18 August 1931; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Colby, Walter F., (Walter Francis), 1880-1980 (Reel 65, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 9 December 1923 - 13 January 1927; 5.0 Item(s) 5 letters (7 pages); Colby, Walter F., (Walter Francis), 1880-1980 (Reel 51, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 24 March 1923 - 1928; 5.0 Item(s) 5 letters (9 pages); Colby, Walter F., (Walter Francis), 1880-1980 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 12, Reel 8, Reel-frame 3, Reel 9, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, Circa 1929; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Colby, Walter F., (Walter Francis), 1880-1980 (Reel 30, Reel-frame 2)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 8 letters, 1923-1955.
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1929-1931; 6.0 Item(s) 6 letters (12 pages); College Entrance Examination Board. (Reel 53, Reel-frame 6, Reel 51, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Collins, E. H. (Reel 62, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1947; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Columbia University. Men's Faculty Club. (Reel 13, Reel-frame 1)